Lecture5：
	https://scs.hosted.panopto.com/Panopto/Pages/Viewer.aspx?id=fa5de5ef-c7be-417b-8a9d-a9e501337dab
The main goal (Lecture5) is to talk about KNN and model selection.

<1> K-NEAREST NEIGHBORS
      1.1 Nearest Neighbor Classifer
	* Train: store D
	* Predict: Assign the label of the nearest point in D
	* [e.g.] NN - predict the point y with the nearest point
      1.2 K-Nearest Neighbor Classifier
	* Train: store D
	* Predict: Assign the "most common" label of the "K" nearest points in D
	* [e.g.] K-NN (K=3) - find the nearest 3 points and decide the label with majority vote, [2+, 1-] => y = +1
      1.3 Distance Functions
	* KNN requires a distance function
	   a) most common choice is Eucldean distance: 
		g(u, v) = sqrt(sum 1 to M, (u_m-v_m)^2)
	   b) other choice are just fine (e.g. Manhattan distance)
		g(u, v) = sum 1 to M, |u_m - v_m|
      1.4 Other remarks
            1.4.1 How to deal with even K? ---> tie for Majority_Vote_Classifier
	a) consider another point, K+1
	b) remove farthest of K point, K-1
	c) weight votes by distance
	d) consider another distance metric
            1.4.2 What is the inductive bias of KNN?
	a) Nearby points should have similar labels
	b) All dimensions are created equally!
	* Problem: feature scale could dramatically influence classification results (i.e. x.axis=cm, y.axis=km)
            1.4.3 Computational efficiency
	* Suppose: N train examples, each one has M features; Computational complexity for special case, where K = 1
	--------------------------------
	*       Task			Naive		k-d tree
	>>> Train			O(1)		~ O(MNlogN)
	>>> Predict(1 test example)	O(MN)		~ O(2^MlogN) on average
	* k-d tree is better, but still not enough
	   a) problem: fast for small M, but slow for large M
	   b) In practice: use "Stochastic approximations"
            1.4.4 Theoretical guarantees
	* Cover & Hart (1967)
	   - assume: h(x) ∈ KNN (K=1, binary) & train example N ---> infinite
	   - result: error_true(h) < 2 * Bayes Error Rate
	* Bayes error rate: "the best you could possibly do"
	* 50% of KNN classification information is true
            1.4.5 Q/A: Which one can reach 0 error rate for "decision boundary"? KNN or DT?
	* KNN: dictate by pixel >>> reach the decision boundary as random-shape boundary
	* DT: dictate by x, y-axis value >>> reach the decision boundary as rectangular boundary

<2> DATASET FOR KNN
      2.1 Fisher Iris Dataset
	* y -> species; x1-> length and x2 -> width
	* a) when K is small, there is noisy point
	   b) when K is infinite, only 1 species left and that is Majority_Vote_Result
      2.2  Gaussian Dataset
	* a) when K is big, the decision boundary is quite "smooth"

<3> MODEL SELECTION
      3.1 Definitions # still premature, fairly simple for both DT & KNN
            - [a] Statistics
	* Def: "Model" defines the data generation process (i.e. a set or family of parametric probability distributions).
	* Def: "Model Parameters" are the values that give rise to a particular probability distribution in the model family.
	* Def: "Learning" (aka. estimation) is the process of finding the parameters that best fit the data.
	* Def: "Hyperparameters" are the parameters of a prior distribution over parameters.
            - [b] Machine Learning
	* Def: (loosely) "Model" defines the hypothesis space over which learning performs its search.
	* Def: "Model Parameters" are the numeric values or structure selected by the learning algorithm that give rise to a hypothesis.	
	* Def: "Learning Algorithm" defines the data-driven search over the hypothesis space. (i.e. search for good parameters)
	* Def: "Hyperparameters" are the tunable aspects of the model, that the learning algorithm does not select.
      3.2 examples
            # Decision Tree
	* model: set of all possible trees, possibly restricted by some hyperparameters (e.g. max-depth)
	* parameters: structure of a specific decision tree
	* learning algorithm: ID3, CART, etc ...
	* hyperparameters: max_depth, threshold for splitting criterion, etc ...
            # K-Nearest Neighbors
	* model: set of all possible nearest neighbors classifier
	* parameters: None (KNN is an instance-based or non-parametrics method)
	* learning algorithm: for naive setting, just storing the data
	* hyperparameters: K, the number of neighbors to consider
            # Perception
	* model: set of all linear separators
	* parameters: vector of weights (1 for each feature)
	* learning algoithms: mistake based updates to the parameters
	* hyperparameters: None (unless some variant such as average perception)
      3.3 Model selection
            3.3.1 Two very similar definitions:
	- Def: "Model Selection" is the process by which we choose the "best" model from among a set of candidates.
	- Def: "Hyperparameter Optimization" is the process by which we choose the "best" hyperparameters from among a set of candidates. 
		(could be called a special case of model selection)
	* BOTH assume access to a function capable of measuring the "quality" of model.
	* BOTH are typically done "outside" the main training algorithm --- typically training is treated as a black box
            3.3.2 #example: KNN
	- [a] Special cases --- hyperparameter K
		* when K = 1 >>> Nearest Neighbor Classifier
		* when K = infinite >>> Majority Vote Classifier
	- [b] Train & Test Error
		* assume dataset contains: 40% y = +1; 60% y = -1
		* then train error is range from 0 to 40%, with K goes from 0,1 to infinite
	- [c] Cross-Validation
		* def. using different subset of training set for validation, and each time using the remain data for training.
		* def. # of fold => n-fold cross-validation
            3.3.3 Cross-Validation
	- [a] definition of Cross-validation: a method of estimating loss on held out data
		* Input: training data, learning algorithm, loss function (e.g. 0/1 error)
		* Output: an estimate of loss function on held-out data
	       # Key idea: use many "validation" set to find stable error rate
	- [b] Algorithm:
		* Divide data into folds (e.g. 4)
		* 4 step train and predict:
		   - Train on folds {1, 2, 3} and predict on {4}
		   - Train on folds {1, 2, 4} and predict on {3}
		   - Train on folds {1, 3, 4} and predict on {2}
		   - Train on folds {2, 3, 4} and predict on {1}
		* Concatenate all the predictions and evaluate loss (almost equivalent to .ave)
      3.4 Summary
	* This section is only scratching the surface!
	* more and more methods for hyperparameter optimization is in future:
	   - Grid search, Random search, Bayesian optimization, Graduate-student descent
	* Main Takeaway:
	   - Model selection / hyperparameter optimization is just another form of learning

<4> THE PERCEPTRON ALGORITHM
      4.1 Linear Models for Classification
	* Commonly used Linear Classifications:
	   - Preceptron, Logistic Regression, Naive Bayes, Support Vector Machines
	* Goal: use decision function to model hyperplane.
	   - h(x) = Sign(θ^T*X) for y ∈ {-1, +1}
      4.2 Geometry
	# E.X. Draw the function w1x1+w2x2+b = 0, where w1 = 2, w2 = 3, b = 6.
	   - Step [1]: w1x1 + w2x2 = 0, x2 = (-w1/w2)x1;
	   - Step [2]: w1x1 + w2x2 + b = 0, x2 = (-w1/w2)x1 + (-b/w2);
	   - Step [3]: W = [[2 3]]^T = [[2][3]]
	* Perceptron Classifier:
	   - y^ = h(x) = Sign(w1x1 + w2x2 + ... + wNxN + b) = Sign(W^T*x + b)
      4.3 Definitions for Geo
	* Def: a vector a is orthogonal to vector b, if ab = a^Tb = 0
	* Def: the l_2 norm of vector u is ||u||_2 = sqrt(sum from m = 1 to |u|, (u_m)^2), where |u| means the dimensional.
	* Def: Hyperplanes >>> in 2D = line
			>>> in 3D = plane
			>>> in 4D = hyperplane
	* Def: hyperplane
	   - A set of points P, where P = {x ∈ R^M: WX + b = 0}
	   * def: half-spaces
	      - P_+ = {x ∈ R^M: WX + b > 0}
	      - p_- = {x ∈ R^M: WX + b < 0}

